在上一堂课的最后，
At the end of the previous lecture,
我们讨论了它会如何
we discussed how it would be nice
能够命名一些元素
to be able to name some elements
然后使用这些名称在 CSS 中选择它们。
and then use those names to select them in CSS.
所以在这个视频中，
And so in this video,
我们将学习使用类和 ID 来做到这一点。
we will learn to do exactly that using Classes and IDs.
所以记得在上一堂课是怎么做的
So remember how in the last lecture
我们只想将这里的文本设置为斜体。
we wanted to style only this text here as italic.
所以这个标题里面的这段，
So this paragraph that is inside this header,
但不是这个其他段落
but not this other paragraph
这也是标题的内部。
that is also inside of a header.
所以我们想出了解决方案
So we came up with the solution
只选择标题内的段落
of selecting only the paragraphs inside of headers
在文章里面。
that are inside of articles.
记住这一点。
Remember that.
问题在于，这本质上是
The problem with this is that this essentially
将 HTML 结构编码到我们的 CSS 选择器中。
encodes the HTML structure into our CSS selector.
这不是一个好主意。
And that is not a good idea.
因此，我们现在基本上将这里命名为这个元素
And so instead we will now basically name this element here
用一个叫做 ID 的东西。
with something called an ID.
就这样，
And so with that,
然后我们可以避免写一个大的
we can then avoid writing a big
和这样的长选择器。
and a long selector like this.
所以我们就到这里吧。
So let's go here.
有问题的段落就是这里的这一段。
And the paragraph in question is this one here.
所以现在我们可以指定一个称为 ID 的特殊属性。
And so now we can specify a special attribute called an ID.
所以这个属性叫做ID。
So the attribute is called ID.
现在让我们简单地称其为作者。
And now let's simply call this one Author.
所以在这里记住这个名字，作者。
So remember this name here, Author.
所以现在这个元素在这里，
And so now this element here,
这一段基本上被称为作者。
this paragraph is basically called Author.
所以现在在 Or CSS 中，我们可以使用 Hash 选择器。
And so now in Or CSS, we can use the Hash selector.
所以这个，其实就是ID选择器。
So this one, which is in fact, the ID selector.
所以哈希，现在是我们刚刚指定的 ID 的名称。
So Hash and now the name of the ID that we just specified.
现在我们可以，
And now here we can,
再一次将字体样式设置为斜体，对吧？
one more time set the font style to italic now, right?
现在我们可以在这里摆脱这段代码
And now we can get rid of this code here
因为不再需要了。
because it's no longer necessary.
现在，与其删除这段代码，
Now, instead of deleting this code,
我真的想把它留在这里。
I actually want to keep it here.
所以我们可以做一些类似于我们在 HTML 中做的事情，
And so we can do something similar as we did in HTML,
我们写评论的地方。
where we wrote comments.
记住这一点。
Remember that.
所以在这里我们写了一些 HTML 注释来保留这段代码
So here we wrote some HTML comments to keep this code here
没有真正活跃，对吧？
without being actually active, right?
所以在 HTML 中，我们也可以这样做。
And so in HTML, we can do the same.
它只是以不同的方式工作。
It just works in a different way.
所以在 CSS 中，
So in CSS,
我们先写一个斜线然后是星
we write a Slash then the Star
然后从这个地方开始
and then from this place on
其他一切都将是评论。
everything else will be a comment.
所以我们需要关闭这个评论
So we need to close this comment
因为我们当然希望此代码处于活动状态。
because of course we want this code to be active.
所以我们现在写相反的。
And so we write now the opposite.
所以星和斜线。
So Star and Slash.
所以现在只有这个是灰色的
So now only this is gray
所以只有这个是评论。
and so only this is the comment.
所以如果我现在保存这个，
So if I save this now,
然后你会看到，事实上，只有这个文本，
then you see that in fact, that only this text,
所以只有这一段是斜体，而不是这一段。
so only this paragraph is italic and not this one.
让我们在这里实际添加另一种样式。
Let's actually add another style here.
所以另一个声明。
So another declaration.
让我们将字体大小设置为 18 像素。
And let's set the font size to 18 pixels.
所以让它变小一点
So make it a bit smaller
因为记住其他段落的大小是 22 像素。
because remember how the other paragraphs are 22 pixels big.
事实上，这里的这个变小了
And indeed this one here got smaller
和所有其他段落，
and all the other paragraphs,
当然包括这里的这个，保持不变。
including of course this one here, stayed the same.
现在让我们做一些类似于这里的版权文本的事情。
Now let's do something similar to the copyright text here.
所以这个，和那个，
00:03:40,410--> 00:03:44,570
然后我们将在此处替换此 CSS 规则。
So this one, and with that,
we will then replace this CSS rule right here.
所以我们可以再次用我刚才的方式评论它，
So we can again, comment it out the way I just did it,
但实际上让我向您展示一个不错的 VS 代码技巧。
but let me actually show you a nice VS code trick.
所以为了注释代码
So in order to comment a code
你以前这样选择的，
that you previously selected like this,
您所要做的就是按 Command 或 Control + Slash。
all you have to do is to hit Command or Control + Slash.
所以我现在就这么做。
So I will do that now.
所以你会自动看到它
And so you see that it automatically
在这里编辑这些评论，对吧？
edit these comments here, right?
如果我然后点击命令或控制
And if I then hit Command or Control
再次在 Windows 上加上 Slash，
on windows plus Slash again,
然后它会关闭评论。
then it turns the comment back off.
所以我可以在这两种模式之间来回切换。
So I can go back and forth between these two modes.
所以如果我们现在重新加载它，
So if we reload this now,
当然它会回到 22 像素。
of course it will be back to 22 pixels.
所以让我们转到我们的 HTML 并给它一个名字。
And so let's go to our HTML and give this one a name.
所以一个使用ID属性的名字。
So a name using the ID attribute.
所以ID，让我们说版权。
So ID, let's say copyright.
然后让我们选择这个文本，
Let's then select this text,
复制它并粘贴到这里。
copy it and just paste it here.
记住我们像这样使用 ID 选择器，
00:04:49,130​​ --> 00:04:51,403
加上我们刚刚指定的名称，
And remember we use the ID selector like this,
plus the name that we just specified,
让我们回到 16 像素的字体大小。
and let's go back to a font size of 16 pixels.
就在这里。
And here it is.
所以它再次起作用了。
So it worked once again.
现在，除了身份证，
Now, besides the ID,
实际上还有另一种给元素命名的方法，
there's actually another way of giving elements names,
这是通过使用类而不是 ID。
which is by using the Class and instead of an ID.
所以我们在这里指定了id属性
So we specified the ID attribute here
给这个元素一个名字，
to give this element a name,
但我们也可以使用 Class 属性。
but we could also have used the Class attribute.
现在ID和类之间的巨大区别
Now the big difference between IDs and Classes
是我们不允许重复ID名称，
is that we are not allowed to repeat ID names,
或者换句话说，
or in other words,
我们只能使用每个 ID 名称一次。
we can only use each ID name only once.
所以现在不允许添加版权ID
So it will not be allowed to now add an ID of copyright
到别的东西。
to something else.
所以我不能，例如，
So I could not for example,
现在去这里添加版权的ID。
now go here and add the ID of copyright.
所以这实际上是无效的 HTML。
So this would actually be invalid HTML.
所以我们不允许这样做。
So we are not allowed to do that.
所以如果我们需要多次重用一个名字，
And so if we need to reuse a name multiple times,
那么我们需要为此使用类。
then we need to use Classes for that.
好的。
Okay.
因此，让我向您展示一个使用类的示例。
So let me show you an example of using Classes.
所以我现在想做的就是在这里给这些作者设置样式
And so what I want to do now is to style these authors here
这三个相关的帖子以不同的方式。
of these three related posts in a different way.
所以基本上这就是这里的P元素
So basically that's this P-element here
还有这个和这个。
and this one and this one.
再说一次，
And so again,
我现在不能使用相关作者的 ID。
I can now not use the ID of say related author.
因此，我需要使用 Class 属性。
So instead I need to use the Class attribute.
我们称它为相关作者。
And let's call it related-author.
所以在 CSS 中，
So in CSS,
这是一个约定，如果我们有一个类或一个 ID 名称
it is a convention that if we have a Class or an ID name
用多个词，
with multiple words,
我们像这样用破折号分隔这些词。
we separate these words by Dashes like this.
例如，您也可以使用下划线。
You could also use Underscores for example.
所以这也是有效的，
So that's also valid,
但这只是 CSS 中的约定
but it's just a convention in CSS
总是像这样使用 Dash。
to always use Dash like this.
好的？
Okay?
所以无论如何，
So anyway,
现在让我们在这里抓住这个
let's now grab this here
并将其粘贴到所有这些段落中。
and paste it to all these paragraphs.
所以相关作者三遍。
So related-author three times.
现在让我们来看看我们的 CSS
And so now let's go to our CSS
并为所有具有此类的元素设置样式。
and style all the elements that have this Class.
所以对于 ID，我们使用 Hash 来选择它们。
So for the IDs, we used the Hash to select them.
对于类，我们使用点。
And for Classes, we use the Dot.
所以这是类选择器。
So this is the Class selector.
好的？
Okay?
所以相关作者。
So related-author.
假设我们想要
And let's say that here we want
假设字体大小为 18 像素。
the font size to be 18 pixels, let's say.
我们还要指定一个新的文本属性
And let's also specify a new text property
我们之前没学过的，就是font-weight。
that we didn't learn before, which is the font-weight.
例如，我们可以使用这个来使文本变为粗体。
So this one we can use to make text bold, for example.
如您所见，也许在这里，有多种选择。
So as you saw, maybe here, there are multiple options.
我们可以使用一些数字，但稍后我们将使用它。
We can use some numbers, but we will use that later.
现在，让我们只使用一个关键字，即 Bold。
For now, let's just use a keyword, which is Bold.
所以让我们保存它以查看结果。
So let's save it to see the results.
事实上，现在只有这三个段落不同。
And indeed now only these three paragraphs are different.
所以他们很大胆，他们更小
So they are bold and they are smaller
比所有其他段落。
than all the other paragraphs.
所以当然在 HTML 中，它们仍然是段落，
So of course in the HTML, they are still paragraphs,
但现在他们在这里得到了这些额外的样式，对吧？
but now they got these additional styles here, right?
现在，也许你现在想知道一些事情，
Now maybe you are wondering something here now,
那就是我们现在实际上，
which is that we are now in fact,
多次选择这些段落，对吗？
selecting these paragraphs multiple times, right?
所以我们这里选择这一段，其实对吧？
So we are selecting this paragraph here, in fact, right?
但我们也在这里选择它
But we are also selecting it here
我们实际上也在此处选择它。
and we are selecting it actually also up here.
所以现在我们三度选择了这一段。
So three times now we selected this paragraph.
所以你可能在想
So you might be thinking
其中哪一个得到实际应用。
which one of these gets applied actually.
所以这不是某种冲突吗？
So isn't this like some kind of conflict?
嗯，简短的回答是
Well, the short answer is
实际上所有这些选择器都适用。
that actually all of these selectors do apply.
所以所有这三个规则
So all of these three rules
三个选择器中的一个确实适用。
of the three selectors do in fact apply.
但我将更多地解释所有这些是如何工作的
But I will explain more about how all of this works
以及为什么它在一个额外的视频中以这种方式工作，
and why it works this way in an extra video,
因为这是非常重要的事情
because this is something really important
为了掌握 CSS，您需要了解这些内容。
that you will need to understand in order to master CSS.
所以这个话题本身就值得专门讲一讲，
And so this topic deserves a special lecture on itself,
这将在本节稍后介绍。
which will be a bit later in this section.
但现在在这里前进，
But now moving forward here,
现在让我给你一个小小的挑战。
let me now actually give you a small challenge.
所以我想做的是删除项目符号
So what I want to do is to remove the bullet points
这里只有这个列表。
of only this list here.
所以请记住，我们为此创建了一个列表。
So remember that we created a list for this.
所以当然，这个现在有要点。
And so of course, this one has bullet points right now.
所以我希望你在这里只选择这个列表，
So I want you to select only this list here,
只有这个元素并删除它的要点。
only this element and remove it's bullet points.
现在我们从未删除任何项目符号。
Now we never removed any bullet points.
因此，让我向您展示它是如何工作的。
So let me show you how it works.
为此，我现在实际上，
And for that, I will now in fact,
选择所有无序列表。
select all the unordered lists.
所以这里我们使用属性列表样式
So here we use the property list-style
并将其设置为无关键字。
and set it to the keyword of None.
好的？
Okay?
所以项目符号从这个中消失了，
So the bullet points disappeared from this one,
也是从这一个。
but also from this one.
所以，正如我所说，
And so, as I said,
我希望你现在在这里只选择这个元素
I want you to now select only this element here
然后删除那里的项目符号。
and then remove the bullet points in there.
我希望你通过使用一个名为 Related 的类来做到这一点。
And I want you to do this by using a Class called Related.
好的？
Okay?
所以让我在这里评论这个。
So let me comment this one here.
所以是的。
And so yeah.
在此列表中的此元素上创建一个类
Create a Class on this element on this list here
然后从这个中删除项目符号点。
and then remove the bullet points from this one.
一旦你完成，我会在一分钟内看到你回来。
And I will see you back here in a minute, once you are done.
好的。
Okay.
因此，让我们从 HTML 开始。
So let's start by going to the HTML.
然后当然这是 UL208
And then of course this here is the UL
我们要选择的。
that we want to select.
记住我是如何希望你使用 Class 的。
And remember how I wanted you to use a Class.
我稍后会解释为什么。
And I will explain a bit later why.
所以我们在这里使用了名为Related的类，
So we used the Class here called Related,
现在我们去我们的CSS
and now we go to our CSS
并使用我们刚刚命名的 Class 选择此元素。
and select this element with the Class that we just named.
所以当然，像这样使用 Class 选择器。
So of course, using the Class selector like this.
而现在只有这一个，
And now only on this one,
我们说 list-style 应该是 None。
we say that list-style should be None.
给它一个保存，
Give it a save,
所以这个仍然有要点
and so this one still has the bullet points
而这个没有。
and this one doesn't.
伟大的。
Great.
所以我们这样做是因为我们不想要这个列表
So we did this because we don't want this list here
实际上看起来像一个列表。
to actually look like a list.
它应该只是语义上的相关帖子列表。
It should only semantically be a list of related posts.
但无论如何，让我们现在回到我们的 HTML
But anyway, let's now go back to our HTML
并谈谈我们为什么使用 Class
and talk a little bit about why we used a Class
而不是身份证。
and not an ID.
因为事实上，
Because in fact,
相关帖子只有一个列表元素，对吗？
there's only one list element of Related posts, right?
所以我们可以很容易地将其称为 ID，对吧？
So we could easily have called this an ID, right?
因为记住ID是四个名字
Because remember that the IDs are four names
只使用一次，
that are only used once,
而使用类
while Classes are used
当我们想给多个元素同名时。
when we want to give multiple elements the same name.
所以当我们想要为多个元素设置样式时
So when we want to style multiple elements
在 CSS 中也是如此。
the same way in CSS.
所以知道了这一点，
So knowing about that,
为什么我告诉你使用 Class 而不是 ID？
why did I tell you to use a Class and not an ID?
嗯，原因是通常在现实世界中，
Well, the reason for that is that usually in the real world,
我们从不使用 ID。
we never use IDs.
我们总是使用类，因为通过使用类，
We always use Classes because by using Classes,
我们为未来做好了准备。
we are prepared for the future.
所以想象一下我们实际上使用了一个相关的ID，
So imagine that we used in fact, an ID of Related,
但在稍后的某个时间点，在页面的某个地方，
but then at some point later, somewhere on the page,
我们想添加另一个相关帖子列表。
we wanted to add another list of related posts.
也许我们想要一个在侧边栏中
Maybe we wanted one in the sidebar
我们想要一个在页脚。
and we wanted one in the footer.
所以想象一个更复杂的布局。
So imagining a more complex layout.
那完全有可能，对吧？
That would completely be possible, right?
但是，如果我们一开始就使用了相关的 ID，
But then if we had used an ID of Related in the beginning,
我们现在必须返回并将该 ID 更改为 Class
we would now have to go back and change that ID to a Class
这样我们现在就可以添加另一个相关帖子列表。
so that we could now add another list of related posts.
所以这将是错误的来源
And so that would be a source of error
如果我们出于某种原因忘记了这一点。
if we've, for some reason, forgot that.
而且我们还必须去我们的CSS
And we would also have to go to our CSS
并在那里改变。
and change that there.
所以起初它是一个相关的ID，
So at first it was an ID of Related,
我们现在必须回到这里并将其更改为点。
we would now have to come back here and change it to a Dot.
所以对于类选择器。
So to the Class selector.
虽然这似乎不是一个大问题，
And while this doesn't seem to be a big problem,
它实际上会导致错误。
it can actually lead to bugs.
如果我们有一个非常大的项目，那么代码中的错误也是如此。
So to errors in the code if we have a really big project.
所以默认情况下，
And so by default,
我们只是避免了这个潜在的问题
we simply avoid this potential problem
通过简单地总是使用类。
by simply always using Classes.
好的。
Okay.
现在，我仍然会为您保留此 ID。
Now I will still keep this ID here for you.
所以这个版权ID和这个作者ID，
So this ID of copyright and this ID of author,
只是为了让您也知道如何使用 ID，
just so you also know how to work with IDs,
但在未来，
but in the future,
我实际上将不再使用 ID
I will actually no longer use IDs
因为正如我刚才所说，在现实世界中，
because as I just said in the real world,
我们总是使用类，
we simply always use Classes,
即使我们只使用一次类名。
even if we only use the Class name once.
因为这样做，
Because by doing that,
我们正在让我们的代码为未来做好准备
we are making our code ready for the future
和为潜在的变化做好准备。
and ready for potential changes.
好的。
Okay.
所以我希望这是有道理的。
So I hope that made sense.
如果你愿意，你现在可以继续
And you can now go ahead if you want
并命名更多元素
and name some more elements
并以不同的方式设计它们，
and style them in different ways,
如果你喜欢的话。
if you feel like it.
所以基本上要练习一下，
So basically to practice this a little bit,
然后如果你愿意
and then if you'd like,
你可以跟我一起看下一个视频
you can come with me to the next video
我们将开始使用颜色。
where we will start working with colors.